so i had a bit of an epiphany this
morning while watching
uh kiki's channel or her other channel
her vlog channel
called kiki meets world something along
those lines and she posted a video a
week ago that she's going through an
existential crisis
and watching that video of her talking
about it was eye-opening
in why again influence our culture is
not who we want to be looking to for
this particular crisis
because they are new to this
an existential crisis is a new
phenomenon to them
the people i know who are in game b the
people i know who are saving the world
are people who are the opposite of
influencers who have had
the happen to them health-wise
family-wise
trauma-wise their whole life and
strangely that doesn't lead to you
wanting to be on youtube and wanting to
share that and broadcast that to
everyone
and so um but it does lead to having
gone through an existential crisis your
whole life
and so the people who are better
prepared for this crisis are the very
ones who will not be the influencers
and the influencers are going through
the existential crisis just like
everyone else
but they're babies at it they don't know
it's it's a brand new feeling to them
and that i was like oh yes
existential crisis i've been doing that
since i was a child
especially since i was a teenager when
christianity evaporated from my life and
was like oh what do you mean the church
and god aren't
real what's real um
she talks about in the beginning of this
video she's mentioned some backhand com
comments about how she's she's basically
depressed right now
but how she's not like one of those
people who wears it as like part of
their personality
and i'm like right because it's not part
of your personality
your baseline is pretty happy my
baseline is pretty happy
to feel and yet when i get down for a
day or two it sucks it sucks for
everyone it's like
there's no end to this darkness i know
there's an end it ends in two days
always every time i can't do it for
three or four days like it can't happen
i have to have that light my body gives
it to me my mind gives it to me because
it's like that's not your normal
because it's not my normal but if it is
your normal getting down on those people
because it's part of their personality
yeah strangely strangely it is part of
their personality
they're not and she talks about how you
know that the content she makes that she
wants to make isn't necessarily the
stuff that's watched the most
and so she has to tweak her stuff yeah
it's part of being an influencer
and that's part of the problem with
influencer culture
is that it's you it's not your authentic
self putting out authentic content that
gets the most
engagement that gets some engagement but
then you're so you start tweaking that
message so you get even more engagement
even more engagement and then you become
the thing that gets engagement as
opposed to what you were there to
present in the first place
so the people who've been going through
existential crisis as their whole life
who've been going through trauma
who've had chronic illness people who've
had mental illness
people who have you know family trauma
and abuse
generally even the influencers who have
that stuff they'll have their one-off
videos where they talk about it but it's
definitely not it's like oh yeah i don't
want that to define me
um and
it's a very different space to be in
than being that depressed person
than being that person in an existential
crisis all of the time
we're not going to give them the
influence at all yet they're exactly who
we need to be influencers right now
like the very people who look like they
don't have their together
kiki looks like she has her kylie looks
like she has her together
and she does to them for the most part
except when the world falls apart and
she doesn't know what to do
because the world's falling apart and
the very people who got to the positions
of
in political power and corporate power
all the people
who were influencers in their generation
the people who were charismatic the
people who
who didn't go through trauma the people
who had
went through less and less trauma and so
then they're at the top because they
could fake it till they make it they get
there and they're like look i'm the best
at being the best to be on the best
and it's like great pandemic what do we
do what do we do you're the best at it
i have no clue this is my first
existential crisis
like right so maybe maybe
we should stop maybe we should stop
looking to the people in power like they
know what they're doing because they
don't
they all got there by faking it till
they make it they
i don't trust experts not because i
don't think anyone's more of an expert
than i am
on anything if i feel the opposite way
to that like everyone's more of an
expert than i am on every subject until
i actually sit and look at what they
know
and those people who pretend they know
what they they're talking about
don't
they can't they can't possibly a doctor
can't know what i need them to know so
they can't be an expert
they don't know nutrition they don't
know the ecosystem
of my body or the ecosystem of the world
that my body lives in
so how can they how can they inform me
on medical stuff if they don't have that
full
picture of information i know enough to
know that full picture
exists even if we don't have access to
it they don't even acknowledge it exists
because they need to be the expert
it's like i'm the expert going to school
for eight years right but you didn't
take cellular biology
you don't know nutrition you didn't read
any of the stuff that you're giving me
you just
learned about the pharmaceutical you
just told me something that contradicted
the thing the pharmaceutical
uh pharmacy person gave me
that there's all of these existential
crisis
that come up in life when the world
doesn't work for you time and time again
what do you mean the government's not
there to give me money when i really
need it
don't we all pay taxes why do i have to
fight so hard for this why it's so hard
to be poor
why is it so hard to be sick why does
somebody have to have
have power over my life because they're
an expert when you're
clearly not an expert so going through
trauma going through chronic illness
going through stuff puts you in a
position to
handle existential crisis better but you
look like you don't
because you've dealt with existential
crisis your whole life
which makes you crazy because
the rest of the world doesn't then the
rest of the world wakes up
did you all know did you all know that
this is yes
yes our governments don't have a
clue what's going on
our doctors don't have a fight they're
the best we have please listen to them
and at the same time it's not enough
just know
there are no experts we don't have
parents
that moment in your childhood happens
later in adulthood but you look back at
your child and realize your parents
never had their together
they didn't know what was going on they
didn't know how they were putting food
on the table and roof over
their head they just hid it from you
that is our governments
that is our leaders in power they don't
have a clue what they are doing
they don't understand economics they
don't understand science they don't
understand
human psychology they don't understand
any of it it's like we didn't learn this
in harvard business school
no no you didn't it didn't learn
existential crisis did you
did you know all right this is already
way too long
but oh for those of you who do know
existential crisis
those of you this is not your first time
at this rodeo
we got to step up we got to help the the
kikis and the kylies of the world
um we got to flip this we got to find
the way to make it broadcast
i'm sorry to stop from it being
broadcast and find the way to make it
more interconnected
and that is like all i want to do is
reach out to kylie and be like come to a
solution raising
that's the it's the solution to
existential crisis
because you feel so small like there's
nothing you can do in this world
it's so big and so much happens and
people you love die
and then it's like oh actually in one
hour we can generate solutions for any
area on this planet
therefore we can generate them for all
areas
and so i can't get people to the
solution i've seen
she could i can't get the people to the
things that will change the world
but the influencers can but the
influencers don't have the solutions
because this is this is their
kindergarten they've never went through
this existential crisis before
this is my phd all day every day
people all day every day
it's like oh you guys don't live in a
permanent existential crisis
how is that not it's like i can't do
small talk all i can do is big
why are we even here do you ever just
like wonder
like why we have cities and why there's
cars and how humans just like came into
this existence
and yet you're all just working nine to
five like just
running on that hamster wheel not taking
a moment to like
why are we living this way we don't have
to
but the first step is people to go
through the existential crisis so
if it's your first time welcome and if
it's not your first time
find some people it's their first time
and hold their hand please
see you next time